Facts of migrants in Germany.
Immigration plays an important role in Germany.
Every fourth citizen has a migration background.
That means at least one part of the population is of foreign origin.
Where is Germany in the world's comparison?
On second place. But the USA leads classic immigration countries like Canada, Australia and Switzerland are behind Germany.
Are most of the immigrants refugees?
No, most of them came in 2018 from Romania, Poland and Bulgaria.
The main motive of all immigrants is to look for work.
Do they all find a job? No.
Almost half of the 2.3 million unemployed people have a migration background.
Their unemployment rate is twice as high.
What is the reason?
The most common reason is lack of language skills.
Another reason is discrimination.
Especially Turkish and Arabic names have a negative effect on applications.
With the same qualification and German name, the chances of finding a job are much higher, according to studies.
Are the migrants welcome in Germany? Yes and no.
52% of Germans think there are too many immigrants.
65% think there is a positive effect on the economy.
Is the German concept of migration background problematic?
Yes, only from the third generation, immigrants become officially German.
In countries like Great Britain and Poland, the migrant stamp has disappeared after one generation.